<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE XML>
<library>
  <book ISBN="8934974126126">
		<title>Khát Vọng Tới Cái Vô Hạn</title>
		<description>Nếu từng có dịp đi tàu hỏa, bạn hẳn biết rằng hai đường ray phải song song với nhau để tàu có thể lăn bánh khắp mọi nơi. Thế nhưng nếu bạn đứng nhìn hai đường ray ấy, dường như chúng gặp nhau ở cuối tầm mắt và tàu không thể đi xa hơn nữa. Điều này thật không hợp lý, vì dù đứng ở Paris và không thể thấy Cannes, chúng ta vẫn có thể đón tàu từ Paris đến dự liên hoan phim tại Cannes. Nghịch lý hơn nữa, một nhà tư tưởng Hi Lạp cổ xưa đã lập luận rằng chuyến tàu của bạn phải đi hết một nửa quãng đường, rồi một nửa của quãng đường còn lại, rồi một nửa của quãng đường còn lại, rồi cứ tiếp tục đến vô hạn, và nếu thế bạn sẽ chẳng bao giờ đến nơi.
			Lập luận rất lôgic này rõ ràng lại không thực tế vì chúng ta luôn có thể đi bất cứ nơi đâu, như một em nhỏ giúp cụ già sang bên kia đường. Khi có được một thời gian vô hạn để du hành vào vũ trụ và chiêm ngưỡng vô số những vì sao, một lúc nào đó bạn sẽ tự hỏi tại sao trời lại tối về đêm. Mà chính sự hiển nhiên ấy cũng đã làm trăn trở bao thế hệ các nhà khoa học, và giúp họ dần làm sáng tỏ vị trí của hành tinh của loài người trong vô hạn của vũ trụ. Qua Khát vọng tới cái vô hạn, Giáo sư Trịnh Xuân Thuận sẽ đưa bạn du hành trong thế giới của Vô hạn, từ thế giới của cái nhỏ nhất đến thế giới của cái lớn nhất, và làm sao những thắc mắc hết sức bình thường đã dẫn đến những khám phá vĩ đại nhất của nhân loại.</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8934974125778">
		<title>Cái Vô Hạn Trong Lòng Bàn Tay</title>
		<description>Nội dung sách đề cập đến cuộc đối thoại của hai nhà khoa học. Một của nhà vật lý thiên văn vốn là phật tử, người mong muốn đem những hiểu biết khoa học của bản thân đối chiếu với những nguồn gốc triết học về sự sống theo quan niệm nhà Phật. Một là nhà khoa học phương Tây trở thành nhà sư, người mà những kinh nghiệm cá nhân đã kích thích ông so sánh hai con đường nhận thức hiện thực khách quan.</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8934974111788">
		<title>Bản Thiết Kế Vĩ Đại</title>
		<description>Nội dung cuốn sách, như tác giả nói ngay từ dòng đầu tiên của chương một, là chuyện "Bí ẩn của kiếp nhân sinh", là những câu hỏi tối hậu về sự sống, vũ trụ và vạn vật: Tại sao phải có cái gì đó chứ không phải là hư không?, Tại sao chúng ta tồn tại?, Tại sao là tập hợp các định luật vật lý cụ thể này chứ không phải các tập hợp khác?
			Đó là những câu hỏi đã từng và luôn luôn làm tất cả chúng ta xao xuyến, ở mức độ khác nhau, với cách tiếp cận khác nhau và trong mức độ hiểu biết khác nhau. Lời giải thì cũng có muôn vàn, từ các truyền thuyết, các câu chuyện cổ tích đến những luận lý đơn thuần dựa trên niềm tin và các lý thuyết khoa học được xây dựng một cách chặt chẽ.
			Trong cuốn sách này, Hawking điểm qua tất cả những chặng đường gian nan đó, để rồi cuối cùng đi đến một lý thuyết khả dĩ nhất, được xem là ứng viên duy nhất cho lý thuyết hoàn chỉnh về vũ trụ, lý thuyết- M: đấy chính là lý thuyết thống nhất mà Einstein đã hy vọng tìm được.
			Hawking cũng viết rằng: "Thực tế là bản thân con người chúng ta- cũng đơn thuần là tập hợp các hạt cơ bản của tự nhiên- có khả năng đi gần đến hiểu biết về các định luật vũ trụ chi phối chúng ta và vũ trụ của chúng ta, đã là một thành công lớn".
			Và tác giả tin rằng, chúng ta sẽ tìm ra bản thiết kế vĩ đại, đặt một dấu son cho cuộc tìm tòi cũng rất vĩ đại kéo dài từ hơn 3000 năm nay.</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8934974116691">
		<title>5 Phương Trình Làm Thay Đổi Thế Giới</title>
		<description>Michael Guillen là giảng viên vật lý và toán học, nhưng ông nổi tiếng hơn cả trong vai trò của một phóng viên, biên tập viên truyền hình với những phóng sự thực tế về thảm họa thiên nhiên.
			"5 phương trình làm thay đổi thế giới" được tuần báo Publisher's Weekly bình chọn là quyển sách hay nhất năm 1995 (trong số 21 quyển sách được chọn). Đó là 5 câu chuyện tuyệt vời trên con đường khoa học đi từ quả táo nổi tiếng đến quả bom nguyên tử... đầy tai tiếng. Albert Einstein và phương trình năng lượng, nhà khoa học người Thuỵ Sĩ Daniel Bernoulli và phương trình thuỷ động lực học, nhà vật lý người Anh Michael Faraday và phương trình điện từ trường, Isaac Newton và phương trình vạn vật hấp dẫn, nhà toán lý người Đức Rudolf Julius Emmanuel Clausius và phương trình nhiệt động lực học - 5 con người và 5 phương trình đã làm thay đổi thế giới!</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8936066703956">
		<title>Hiệu Ứng Cánh Bướm</title>
		<description>Ai mới chính xác là người đã cứu hai tỷ người? Có phải là một người cụ thể nào đó mà chúng ta có thể chỉ đích danh? Chúng ta có thể trở lại quá khứ xa đến mức nào? Chúng ta cần kiểm chứng bao nhiêu người để xác định được người thực sự đã cứu được hai tỷ người.... một con số vẫn tiếp tục tăng lên mỗi phút ?
			Và chúng ta phải tiến về phía trước bao xa trong cuộc sống để cho thấy sự khác biệt mà bạn tạo ra.
			Trong cuốn sách này, Andy Andrews sẽ cung cấp cho chúng ta những ví dụ, cụ thể, sinh động cùng những lời lý giải ngắn gọn, súc tích cho hiện tượng vật lý thú  vị này. Chúng ta sẽ biết rằng, chính những hành động nhỏ bé của mình sẽ là khởi nguồn của các kết quả lớn nhiều năm sau đó. Mọi hành động của chúng ta, dù lớn dù nhỏ cũng gieo một cái nhân (nguyên nhân), từ cái nhân đó sinh sôi nảy nở theo thời gian để tạo nên quả (kết quả). Và hiệu ứng cánh bướm nhấn mạnh đến các yếu tố nguyên nhân rất nhỏ tạo thành một kết quả ngoài sức tưởng tượng.</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8934974099208">
		<title>Tôi Thấy Hoa Vàng Trên Cỏ Xanh</title>
		<description>Ta bắt gặp trong Tôi Thấy Hoa Vàng Trên Cỏ Xanh một thế giới đấy bất ngờ và thi vị non trẻ với những suy ngẫm giản dị thôi nhưng gần gũi đến lạ. Câu chuyện của Tôi Thấy Hoa Vàng Trên Cỏ Xanh có chút này chút kia, để ai soi vào cũng thấy mình trong đó, kiểu như lá thư tình đầu đời của cu Thiều chẳng hạn... ngây ngô và khờ khạo.
			Nhưng Tôi Thấy Hoa Vàng Trên Cỏ Xanh hình như không còn trong trẻo, thuần khiết trọn vẹn của một thế giới tuổi thơ nữa. Cuốn sách nhỏ nhắn vẫn hồn hậu, dí dỏm, ngọt ngào nhưng lại phảng phất nỗi buồn, về một người cha bệnh tật trốn nhà vì không muốn làm khổ vợ con, về một người cha khác giả làm vua bởi đứa con tâm thầm của ông luôn nghĩ mình là công chúa,... Những bài học về luân lý, về tình người trở đi trở lại trong day dứt và tiếc nuối.
			Tôi Thấy Hoa Vàng Trên Cỏ Xanh lắng đọng nhẹ nhàng trong tâm tưởng để rồi ai đã lỡ đọc rồi mà muốn quên đi thì thật khó.</description>
	</book>
	<book ISBN="8934974119814">
		<title>Ngồi Khóc Trên Cây</title>
		<description>Nước mắt đâu phải chỉ dành cho nỗi buồn khi người ta có thể khóc vì niềm vui và hạnh phúc. Với Nguyễn Nhật Ánh nước mắt còn là một cái gì đó thiêng liêng, đẹp đẽ và đầy mơ mộng khi ông kể về câu chuyện tình yêu trong sáng và ngây thơ giữa cô bé Rùa và anh chàng Đông trong truyện ngắn “Ngồi khóc trên cây”.
			Tình yêu trong sáng như đóa hoa vừa chớm nở.
			Rùa là cô bé của thiên nhiên, hồn nhiên, trong sáng nhưng lại đầy khí chất mạnh mẽ. Hoàn cảnh cơ cực từ nhỏ đã cho em một sự cứng rắn, với mái tóc cháy nắng trên khuôn mặt khả ái. Còn Đông là cậu sinh viên thành phố về thăm quê, là đứa duy nhất chơi với con Rùa, nói chuyện, lắng nghe, và đồng tình với nó.
			Tâm hồn chúng đồng điệu vào nhau như những đóa hoa dại mới chớm nở đã vội hòa quyện hương thơm phảng phất đầu mùa. Nụ hôn đầu vụng dại trong khu vườn  đã diễn ra một cách nhẹ nhàng, bỡ ngỡ mà cũng thật đáng yêu. Cái ngượng đến chín mặt của Đông khi cả hai môi kề môi được tác giả miêu tả một cách tỉ mỉ đã báo hiệu cho một tình yêu trong sáng, hồn nhiên đang nảy nở.</description>
	</book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-78328-953-0">
    <title>RESTful Web Services with Dropwizard</title>
    <description>The RESTful Web Services concept is constantly growing compared to SOAP technologies. Used by many API providers, RESTful has started to become the architecture of choice for the enterprise SOA as well. Dropwizard combines everything needed to create production ready RESTful Web Services, combining the most powerful, stable and well-known RESTful Java-based libraries. This practical guide will help you learn how to create, configure, and implement a dynamic Web Service application by showcasing practical examples using the most important modules of Dropwizard and combining them together.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-4493-9321-2">
    <title>Head First jQuery</title>
    <description>Want to add more interactivity and polish to your websites? Discover how jQuery can help you build complex scripting functionality in just a few lines of code. With Head First jQuery, you'll quickly get up to speed on this amazing JavaScript library by learning how to navigate HTML documents while handling events, effects, callbacks, and animations. By the time you've completed the book, you'll be incorporating Ajax apps, working seamlessly with HTML and CSS, and handling data with PHP, MySQL and JSON. If you want to learn - and understand - how to create interactive web pages, unobtrusive script, and cool animations that don't kill your browser, this book is for you.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-119-07085-6">
    <title>Professional Python</title>
    <description>Professional Python goes beyond the basics to teach beginner- and intermediate-level Python programmers the little-known tools and constructs that build concise, maintainable code. Design better architecture and write easy-to-understand code using highly adoptable techniques that result in more robust and efficient applications. Coverage includes Decorators, Context Managers, Magic Methods, Class Factories, Metaclasses, Regular Expressions, and more, including advanced methods for unit testing using asyncio and CLI tools. Each topic includes an explanation of the concept and a discussion on applications, followed by hands-on tutorials based on real-world scenarios. The "Python 3 first" approach covers multiple current versions, while ensuring long-term relevance. Python offers many tools and techniques for writing better code, but often confusing documentation leaves many programmers in the dark about how to use them. This book shines a light on these incredibly useful methods, giving you clear guidance toward building stronger applications.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-4493-9991-7">
    <title>Head First C</title>
    <description>Ever wished you could learn C from a book? Head First C provides a complete learning experience for C and structured imperative programming. With a unique method that goes beyond syntax and how-to manuals, this guide not only teaches you the language, it helps you understand how to be a great programmer. You'll learn key areas such as language basics, pointers and pointer arithmetic, and dynamic memory management. Advanced topics include multi-threading and network programming - topics typically covered on a college-level course. We think your time is too valuable to waste struggling with new concepts. Using the latest research in cognitive science and learning theory to craft a multi-sensory learning experience, Head First C uses a visually rich format designed for the way your brain works, not a text-heavy approach that puts you to sleep.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-4493-9330-4">
    <title>Head First Android Development</title>
    <description>Android devices are stealing market share from the iPhone with dramatic speed, and you have a killer app idea. Where to begin? Head First Android Development will help you get your first application up and running in no time with the Android SDK and Eclipse plug-in. You'll learn how to design for devices with a variety of different screen sizes and resolutions, along with mastering core programming and design principles that will make your app stand out. Whether you're a seasoned iPhone developer who wants to jump into the the Android Market, or someone with previous programming skills but no mobile apps in your resume, this book offers a complete learning experience for creating eye-catching, top-selling Android applications.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-4493-8267-4">
    <title>Head First Python</title>
    <description>Ever wished you could learn Python from a book? Head First Python is a complete learning experience for Python that helps you learn the language through a unique method that goes beyond syntax and how-to manuals, helping you understand how to be a great Python programmer. You'll quickly learn the language's fundamentals, then move onto persistence, exception handling, web development, SQLite, data wrangling, and Google App Engine. You'll also learn how to write mobile apps for Android, all thanks to the power that Python gives you. We think your time is too valuable to waste struggling with new concepts. Using the latest research in cognitive science and learning theory to craft a multi-sensory learning experience, Head First Python uses a visually rich format designed for the way your brain works, not a text-heavy approach that puts you to sleep.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-118-83207-3">
    <title>Professional AngularJS</title>
    <description>Most of the existing guides to AngularJS struggle to provide simple and understandable explanations for more advanced concepts. As a result, some developers who understand all the basic concepts of AngularJS struggle when it comes to building more complex real-world applications. Professional AngularJS provides a thorough understanding of AngularJS, covering everything from basic concepts, such as directives and data binding, to more advanced concepts like transclusion, build systems, and automated integration testing. In addition to explaining the features of AngularJS, this book distills real-world experience on how these features fit together to enable teams to work together more effectively in building extraordinary apps.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-78588-138-1">
    <title>Internet of Things with Python</title>
    <description>Internet of Things (IoT) is revolutionizing the way devices/things interact with each other. And when you have IoT with Python on your side, you'll be able to build interactive objects and design them. This book lets you stay at the forefront of cutting-edge research on IoT. We'll open up the possibilities using tools that enable you to interact with the world, such as Intel Galileo Gen 2, sensors, and other hardware. You will learn how to read, write, and convert digital values to generate analog output by programming Pulse Width Modulation (PWM) in Python. You will get familiar with the complex communication system included in the board, so you can interact with any shield, actuator, or sensor. Later on, you will not only see how to work with data received from the sensors, but also perform actions by sending them to a specific shield. You'll be able to connect your IoT device to the entire world, by integrating WiFi, Bluetooth, and Internet settings. With everything ready, you will see how to work in real time on your IoT device using the MQTT protocol in python.</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-78588-866-3">
  	<title>ArcGIS for JavaScript Developers by Example</title>
  	<description>
  		The book starts by explaining the basics of the ArcGIS web mapping ecosystem. The book walks you through the development of six major applications, covering a wide variety of topics such as querying, rendering, advanced data visualization and performing map analytics. It also emphasizes on writing modular code using pure dojo, which is the preferred platform for developing web GIS applications using ArcGIS JavaScript API. By the end of the book, you will have gained enough practical experience to architect a robust and visually powerful mapping application using the API.
  	</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="9780071737708">
  	<title>Complete Digital Design: A Comprehensive Guide to Digital Electronics and Computer System Architecture</title>
  	<description>
  		The explosion in communications and embedded computing technologies has brought with it a host of new skill requirements for electrical and electronics engineers, students, and hobbyists. With engineers expected to have such diverse expertise, they need comprehensive, easy-to-understand guidance on the fundamentals of digital design.<br /><br />Enter McGraw-Hill’s Complete Digital Design. Written by an experienced electrical engineer and networking hardware designer, this book helps you understand and navigate the interlocking components, architectures, and practices necessary to design and implement digital systems. It includes:<br /><br />* Real world implementation of microprocessor-based digital systems<br />* Broad presentation of supporting analog circuit principles<br />* Building complete systems with basic design elements and the latest technologies<br /><br />Complete Digital Design will teach you how to develop a customized set of requirements for any design problem — and then research and evaluate available components and technologies to solve it. Perfect for the professional, the student, and the hobbyist alike, this is one volume you need handy at all times!
  	</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-49194-074-7">
  	<title>Learning Swift</title>
  	<description>
  		Get hands-on experience with Apple's Swift programming language by building real working apps. With this practical guide, skilled programmers with little or no knowledge of Apple development will learn how to code with Swift 2 by developing three complete, tightly linked versions of the Notes application for the OS X, iOS, and watchOS platforms. In the process, you'll learn Swift's fundamentals, including its syntax and features, along with the basics of the Cocoa, CocoaTouch, and WatchKit frameworks. This book teaches you how to use common design patterns for Swift, how to structure an application for Apple's platforms, and how to submit working apps to the App Store.
  	</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-1-4493-1428-6">
  	<title>High Performance MySQL, 3rd Edition</title>
  	<description>
  		How can you bring out MySQL's full power? With High Performance MySQL, you'll learn advanced techniques for everything from designing schemas, indexes, and queries to tuning your MySQL server, operating system, and hardware to their fullest potential. This guide also teaches you safe and practical ways to scale applications through replication, load balancing, high availability, and failover. Updated to reflect recent advances in MySQL and InnoDB performance, features, and tools, this third edition not only offers specific examples of how MySQL works, it also teaches you why this system works as it does, with illustrative stories and case studies that demonstrate MySQL's principles in action. With this book, you'll learn how to think in MySQL.
  	</description>
  </book>
  <book ISBN="978-0-596-80272-1">
  	<title>Mac OS X Snow Leopard Pocket Guide</title>
  	<description>
  		Whether you're new to the Mac or a longtime user, this handy book is the quickest way to get up to speed on Snow Leopard. Packed with concise information in an easy-to-read format, Mac OS X Snow Leopard Pocket Guide covers what you need to know and is an ideal resource for problem-solving on the fly. This book goes right to the heart of Snow Leopard, with details on system preferences, built-in applications, and utilities. You'll also find configuration tips, keyboard shortcuts, guides for troubleshooting, lots of step-by-step instructions, and more.
  	</description>
  </book>
</library>

